Hope has yet to abandon these lands.
The Lord of the Rings: The War of the Rohirrim is a animation,
fantasy, adventure film directed by Kenji Kamiyama.
A sudden attack by Wulf, a clever and traitorous lord of Rohan seeking vengeance for the death of his father, forces Helm
Hammerhand, the King of Rohan, and his people to make a daring last stand in the ancient stronghold of the Hornburg.
Helm Hammerhand (voice), played by Brian Cox.
Héra (voice), played by Gaia Wise.
Wulf (voice), played by Luke Pasqualino.
Fréaláf (voice), played by Laurence Ubong Williams.
Olwyn (voice), played by Lorraine Ashbourne.
Éowyn (voice), played by Miranda Otto.
The Lord of the Rings: The War of the Rohirrim is a 2024 anime fantasy film directed by Kenji Kamiyama from a screenplay by
Jeffrey Addiss & Will Matthews and Phoebe Gittins & Arty Papageorgiou, based on characters created by J.
Set around 200 years before Peter Jackson's The Lord of the Rings (2001–2003) and The Hobbit
(2012–2014) film trilogies, it tells the story of legendary Rohan king Helm Hammerhand.
When the neighboring Dunlendings propose a marriage to his daughter Héra, Helm
unintentionally kills their leader in a fistfight and starts a war.
The film stars Brian Cox as Helm and Gaia Wise as Héra, alongside Luke
Pasqualino, Laurence Ubong Williams, Lorraine Ashbourne, and Miranda Otto.
Presented by New Line Cinema, it was produced by Warner Bros.
Animation and Sola Entertainment in association with
WingNut Films and Domain Entertainment.
The film was announced in June 2021 and development was fast-tracked to prevent New
Line from losing the film adaptation rights for Tolkien's novels.
Kamiyama was involved by then, as were producer Philippa Boyens—who
co-wrote Jackson's films—and writers Addiss and Matthews.
Gittins and Papageorgiou re-wrote the script, which is based on details in the appendices of
Tolkien's novel The Lord of the Rings (1954–55) covering the history of Rohan's rulers.
They chose to focus on Helm's daughter, who is unnamed in the appendices.
Sola Entertainment provided the traditional 2D animation,
taking visual inspiration from Jackson's films.
The main cast was revealed in June 2022, including Miranda Otto, reprising her
role from Jackson's trilogy as Éowyn, who narrates the film.
Jackson and his trilogy co-writer Fran Walsh were being
credited as executive producers by June 2024.
The Lord of the Rings: The War of the Rohirrim premiered on December
3, 2024, and was released theatrically by Warner Bros.
Pictures in international markets from December 5 and
in the United States on December 13.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $20.7
million worldwide against a $30 million production budget.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
prequel, treachery, fantasy world, anime.